

Matthew Jeffery



Dunedin **New Zealand**

Mobile:

Email: matthewjeffery07@gmail.com

Linkedin: https://nz.linkedin.com/in/matthew-jeffery-3bb04a108

Personal statement

I am currently studying a Bachelor's Degree in IT, with a keen interest and strong introductory knowledge in software programming. I am a hardworking, enthusiastic worker. I am very adaptable to the work environment in which I work and am always energetic, focused and ready for the work at hand. I have worked in a diversity of jobs ranging from casual engineering to dairy milking and writing formal reports in an office environment. I can work both in groups and individually efficiently.

Skills

Strong computer skills Can work under stress Great work ethic Fast typing (70 WPM)

Understands, computer terminology comprehensively. Very confident with Microsoft software including: Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook, Access and

Confident introductory knowledge in the following programming languages:

HTML & CSS JavaScript Java C#

PHP MySQL / PDO

Linux Command Line Windows Command Line

JQuery

Work History

Internship, Abacus Biotechnology, Dunedin v2015-2016 I worked on reviewing and analysing various online databases for large commercial beekeeping industries. This mainly included working with the Farm Management System, FarmIQ. This internship taken place over the summer holidays of 2015.

Relief Milker, Inch Clutha, Balclutha 2015 – Present

I worked mid-year holidays of 2015 and over the summer holidays of 2016. Working early hours from 4am. Herding and milking cows. Maintaining a clean workspace and lots of weed spraying/grubbing. Understanding of Dairy Milking process.

Cashier/Casual Work, Guy Wong & Son (GWS), Balclutha 2014-2015

I worked over the summer holidays of 2014 and worked some weekends throughout the year whenever I was needed. Jobs included cashier, cleaning, stacking shelves with fresh produce.

Casual Worker, Calder Stewart, Milton 2012 – 2013

I worked as a casual worker at Calder Stewart over the summer holidays for 2 years. This work mainly included cutting and grinding steel.

Light Metal Engineer, Rinnon Products, Dunedin 2009 – 2011

I worked at Rinnon products for one year part time after school as a casual worker. Work mainly consisted of constructing brake shoes for trains.

Education

South Otago High School, Balclutha - NCEA Level 1 - 2013

South Otago High School, Balclutha - NCEA Level 2 - 2014

Otago Polytechnic, Dunedin — Certificate in level 4 Business - 2015

Otago Polytechnic, Dunedin - Current second year Bachelor of IT student - 2015-Present

Interests and Hobbies

I enjoy solving other people's programming problems and helping others within my course, learning new things regarding computer programming and improving my general professional knowledge to advance in my career. I also enjoy mountain biking, farming and video games.

References

Abacus Biotechnology: Simon Glennie –



Course programming Lecturer: Dale Parsons – (03) 474-84